MATT BENSON

Seattle, WA 98103

Phone: 425-614-9155 | Email: rabenson6@msn.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/matt-benson-b7a24a91/ | Github: https://github.com/Bensonm3 |

Portfolio: https://dry-temple-73836.herokuapp.com/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Political Science, International Business, and a passion for learning. Seasoned project manager with 5 years of experience, capable of working independently and collaborating with teams across multiple functions. Hands on experience coding in Javascript, HTML, and CSS and working with React,

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, HTML, CSS

Applications: React, Typescript, Node.js, Express.js, Bootstrap, jQuery, Git, MySQL, NoSQL, IndexDB,

MongoDB, Bash

PROJECTS

Fair Weather Hiking | Github | https://fair-weather-hiking.herokuapp.com/login

- Hiking App developed in React to display hike weather conditions and provide user specific hiking statistics
- Participated with a team of 4 in all phases of the development life cycle, focusing on coding, testing, and debugging.
- Created and developed remotely, collaborating with team members using Zoom and Slack
- Created the app concept and pitched it to team members, who agreed to develop the idea into a full application.
- Developed and organized API calls and completed hike info tracking.
- Spearheaded app demonstration and presented final product to peers and industry professionals
- React, Hiking Project API, Open Weather API, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, Node.js, Redux, and Materialize CSS used for this project

Get Outside | Github | https://bmalkmus.github.io/getOutsideApp/

- Collaborated with a team of 3 to develop a Javascript app allowing a user to plan a day at a park and a meal from a restaurant
- Individual contributions include the creation of the the app concept, API Calls, and search form functionality created with Javascript
- Led a demonstration of the app to peers and a teacher, and held a Q&A after the demo.
- Javascript, Seattle Parks API, Zomato API, Materialize CSS, and HTML used for this project

Employee Directory | Github | https://mrbemployeedb.herokuapp.com/

- Created Interactive Employee Database app developed in React as a solo project to optimize employee data retrieval
- Developed search bar which allows the user to search employees by first name, last name, or location
- Designed sort function which allows the user to sort by years of service ascending or descending
- React, HTML, Javascript, and CSS used for this project

EXPERIENCE

Inventory Control Specialist Costco Wholesale

February 2018 - Present Issaguah, WA

Provided logistical and operational support to vendors and international warehouses for supply chain tactics. Ensured product compliance and streamlined product standards protocols in international marketplaces. *Key Accomplishments:*

- Established relationships with vendors to ensure customer satisfaction and resolve supply chain issues
- Successfully negotiated and supported vendor funded markdowns and promotions of key products.
- Contributed to successful openings in new markets including China and Western Australia, with higher than projected sales
- Drove continual sales increases through introduction of new items and timely in store promotions, meeting or exceeding annual projections in most markets

Tax Accountant Costco Wholesale

July 2013 - February 2018

Issaquah, WA

Independently managed and reviewed sales tax refund claims for online and in-store purchases as a forward facing customer service representative. Participated in state audits of sales tax returns.

Kev Accomplishments:

- Successfully automated aspects of the sales tax refund claim process increasing efficiency and reducing processing time by 66%
- Contributed to department tax knowledge through deep research on new and upcoming sales tax issues, ensuring readiness to tackle future upcoming issues.
- Earned the trust of retail customers through strong customer service, continual communication, and minimizing tax refund processing times

Reservation Agent

Costco Travel

November 2012 - July 2013

Issaguah, WA

Arranged and coordinated cruise reservations for customers. Maintained product expertise to ensure customers have the best possible experience.

Key Accomplishments:

- Received Excellence Award twice in two guarters of eligibility
- Successfully placed reservations and made adjustments based on customer needs.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Washington Professional and Continuing Education, Seattle, WA A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelors of Arts: Western Washington University, Bellingham, WA Four year university degree focused on political science, economics and policy.

Politics Exchange Program: University of Hull, Hull, East Yorkshire, UK Single Semester Foreign Exchange, studying British Politics and History